

Website: http://kolev.io

Email: p.kolev22@gmail.com

Github: https://github.com/plamen-kolev

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/plamen-kolev-465915a7

ABOUT

My name is Plamen Kolev and I am a Newcastle, England based developer specializing in web application development, system automation and Web Application deployment. I enjoy playing with emerging technologies and stay up to date with tech trends.

In the past years, I have gained knowledge in Perl, Bash, Unix-based operating systems, python for web development and PHP.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer Intern, Intel August 2015 - September 2016

Worked on high-performing, cyber security projects. Created automated tests using bash, Perl and in-house tools. Developed scripts to automate product integration and deployment in a large, multi-national team

April 2014 - June 2015 Data Solutions

Conducted national studies across Britain on sociopolitical issues

Lead Graphic Designer, Ivesto September 2012 - June 2013

Worked full time as a website manager and designer where I had the opportunity to improve the user experience and maintain the two websites of the company.

EDUCATION

BSc. Computer Science, Newcastle
September 2013 - Present

Object-oriented programing, design & development of software. Web design & construction: delivery and consumption of web content, database technologies. Computer Architecture: Parallel Computer Architectures Low-level programing. Software Engineering - principles and life cycle, scalability and maintenance. Team projects, working as part of a group.

PROJECTS

Web Platform for Digital Deployment of November 2016 - Present

Currently creating a platform for deployment, management and monitoring of virtual servers as part of final year dissertation.

Technologies used: chef, bash shell, virtualbox, vagrant, ruby, ruby on rails.

5 August - 28 August 2016

Created a PHP website for the neven brand, the website is deployed here. Website features internatiolization and stripe payment integration.

5 May 2016 ng Presentation

Gave a presentation in Lester College about writing code and the potential attacks that a malicious user can perform

September 2014 - March 2015

Developed and designed a website with restful API that hooks to an Android application for the British bank Lloyds. The product was produced as part of a team.

31 October 2014 hon

Co-organized a hackathon in the North East, United Kingdom backed by Major League Hacking EU. Created the website for the event, PR and print design materials.

12 February 2014

Developed an environmental friendly hardware & software solution with the Raspberry Pi that involves predictive light automation and control.